Good morning Church !
Good morning !
You may be seated, thank you Lord !
Hallelujeh !
My time does not work; God's time works.
Tell your neighbor !
When the case is very tight, you begin to speak to yourself
I don't know... where is ...
I am sorry !
Your time does not work; God's time does.
Hallelujeh !
The book of Roman 10
verse 1
Romans 10:1 "Brothers and sisters, my heart's desire and prayer to God for the Israelites is that they may be saved."
That is prayer for Israelites.
Romans 10:2 "For I can testify about them that they are zealous for God, but their zeal is not based on Knowledge."
That is on knowledge of truth.
Romans 10:3 "Since they did not know the righteousness of God and sought to establish their own,"
Romans 10:3 "they did not submit to God's righteousness."
As a Christian, with the heart, man testifies, man knows that Jesus is righteousness.
We are the righteousness of God in Christ Jesus.
Let's go to the proof text
verse 9
Romans 10:9 "If you declare with your mouth, 'Jesus is Lord,'
and believe in your heart that God raised him from the dead,
you will be saved."
With the heart, we know Christ is righteousness.
But on their own, they have not yet declared
in their heart, that God raised Jesus from the dead.
They are not yet !
Belief in the heart
Say to yourself, belief in the heart
As the Bible states it, belief in my heart.
Belief in your heart.
Belief in their heart.
Just as there is a faith towards our Lord Jesus Christ for salvation.
There is a faith towards the Holy Spirit, Holy Ghost for power,
Tell your neighbor !
Just as there is a faith towards our Lord Jesus for salvation.
There is a faith towards the Holy Ghost for power.
We are talking about the belief in their heart.
Belief in your heart, belief in my heart.
Anyway you see we talk about heart, man's heart !
Man's spirit, man's heart. Man's spirit, man's heart.
The more you meditate about what you read in the Bible,
the more your spirit, that is your heart, acts upon the Word you read.
In a literal way, the word, 'meditate' means 'think' -
How can you get the Word into our heart, into our spirit ?
You get the Word into your spirit when you read your Bible slowly, attentively and repeatedly.
It's not the kind you reading in school.
You know when you are reading for your academic.
You have to read and you have to read fast.
So fast, you understand what you're reading ? No. That's not...
You must be carried along by the Holy Spirit when you are reading the Bible.
That is why you have to wait for the Holy Spirit.
Tell your neighbor: Wait for the Holy Spirit.
I can't heat you.
Wait for the Holy Spirit !
Read slowly, attentively and repeatedly.
You know while you are reading, you just read, because you understand what you are reading.
That understanding is mental action.
Intellectual agreement.
Intellectual creation.
To take the word into our heart, into our spirit,
you must read your Bible slowly, attentively and repeatedly.
When you read something slowly, it means you give all your attention.
If there are many things to think about, you can't read slowly.
You can't even meditate if there are things around to overwhelm you.
So, It means to read slowly is to stay focused.
'Attentively' means off, on the outside, on, on the inside.
That is attentively.
'Repeatedly' means you have to go back again, trying to figure out the message that is personal.
and insert your name where the message is personal.
That is repeatedly - you have to go back again.
I know you don't understand what you have read.
But you just have to understand it in God's way.
In the Holy Spirit way, you have to go back again..(to Bible text)
and look at those message that are personal, you can insert your name.
We are talking to ourself as if we are Sunday school children.
If you know your level in the spirit, you would know you a baby.
When it comes to the things of the spirit, you are a graduate.
You are in... just a kindergarten
You are just learning A, B, C....
We have to go back again, because you soon forget.
That's the thing of the spirit.
Let us say: A, B, C
A, B, C
Say it again, you have forgotten
That's the thing of the spirit.
This is way we have to go back again.
We need to come back to this issue of faith.
becase many of us are doing foolish things and call it faith.
We are doing foolish things and call it what ?
Faith
Good example
You tried to imitate me
Because I brougt a car, after minister the morning water 3 times,
Immediately you listen to that,
you tell (ask) your neighbor around you, where is that morning water ?
They say is the opposite